--==本影片由 CMCT 团队 荣誉出品==--
更多精彩影视 请访问 http://www.cmct.tv
影片压制：死亡骑士　字幕调校：死亡骑士　招募Q号：76846146
片名：机械姬
收到重要电邮 主题：员工抽奖
"头奖"
安迪 我中奖了
- 不会吧 当真？- 对 当真
好消息 兄弟
天啊 太棒了
带我去？
还要多久才会抵达他的庄园？
How long until we get to his estate?
过去两小时 都在他的庄园上飞行
We've been flying over his estate for the past two hours.
你要把我留在这里？
You're leaving me here?
这是我被允许降落 最靠近建筑物的地方
This is as close as I'm allowed to get to the building.
什么建筑物？
What building?
沿着河走
Follow the river.
知道了
Got it.
把头压低 远离螺旋桨
Keep your head down and get clear of the rotors.
好的
Okay.
无网络讯号
凯莱布·史密斯
Caleb Smith.
是的
Yes.
请靠近对讲机 面对荧幕
Please approach the console and face the screen.
哦
Oh!
请取门卡
Take your keycard.
您可以进屋里了
You may now enter the residence.
有人吗？
Hello?
凯莱布·史密斯
Caleb Smith.
嘿
Hey.
老弟
Dude!
我一直很期待这周与你共处
I've been so looking forward to this week with you.
请进 快请进
Come in. Come on in.
谢谢
Thanks.
想来点吃的或喝的 帮你洗尘吗？
You want something to eat or drink after your journey?
- 不了 谢谢 - 确定？
- No. No, thanks, I'm fine. - Sure?
是的
Yeah.
老实说 本来打算
To be honest, I thought we'd have, uh,
一起吃早餐 但是…
breakfast together, but, um...
我不能吃东西
I can't really eat anything.
- 我还在宿醉 - 是喔？
- I got the mother of all fucking hangovers. - Oh, yeah?
老天 你好像根本不相信
Oh, my God, like you wouldn't even believe.
前晚喝太多酒
When I have a heavy night,
隔天早上就得弥补一下
I, uh, compensate the next morning.
运动 服用抗氧化物质等等 懂吗？
Exercise. Anti-oxidants. You know?
懂 当然
Yeah, sure.
派对很棒吗？
Was it a good party?
- 派对？- 对 没有派对吗？
- Party? - Yeah. Wasn't there a party?
没有派对
There wasn't a party.
抱歉
Sorry.
凯莱布 我直话直说 好吗？
Caleb, I'm just gonna throw this out there, so it's said, okay?
你吓到了
You're freaked out.
- 我吗？- 对 你吓到了
- I am? - Yeah. You're freaked out,
被直升机
by the helicopter
群山和房子吓到了
and the mountains and the house,
因为这一切超酷的
because it's all so super-cool.
你此刻被我吓到了
You're freaked out by me, to be meeting me,
竟然跟我共处一室 聊天说话 对吧？
having this conversation in this room, at this moment. Right?
我懂 我懂你此刻的感觉 但…
And I get that. I get the moment you're having, but...
我们能跳过那些吗？
Dude, can we just get past that?
能直接当朋友吗？纳森和凯莱布
Can we just be two guys? Nathan and Caleb.
不是老板和员工
Not the whole employer-employee thing.
- 好 - 好？
- Yeah, okay. - Yeah?
对 好
Yes. Uh, yeah.
我很高兴见到你 纳森
It's good to meet you, Nathan.
我也很高兴见到你 凯莱布
It's good to meet you, too, Caleb.
首先应该说明你的门卡
I guess the first thing I should do is explain your pass.
非常简单
Now, it's simple enough.
有些门能开 有些门不能开
It opens some doors and it doesn't open others.
这样让事情简单点了吧？
And that just makes everything easy for you, right?
对
Uh, yes.
对 因为你会想 我在别人家里
Yeah, 'cause you're like, "Oh, fuck, I'm in someone else's house.
能这样那样吗？
"Can I do this, can I do that?"
有了这张门卡 就不必担心那些事
And this card, it just takes all that worry away.
如果你想开门 门却打不开 很好 那就是禁区
If you try a door and it stays shut, okay, it's off-limits.
你想开另一道门 门开了 那就是你的了
You try another door and it opens, then it's for you.
我们来试这道门
Let's try this one.
我想那是你的了 凯莱布
I guess it's for you, Caleb.
- 喜欢吗？- 喜欢
- You like? - Yeah.
这是你的房间
It's your room.
床在这里
You got a bed here.
浴室在后面这里
A bathroom right back here.
小书桌
Little desk.
橱柜
Cupboards.
小冰箱
Little fridge.
舒服吧？
Cozy, right?
对 很棒
Yeah, this is great.
- 怎么了？- 什么？
- What? - Sorry?
不对劲 怎么了？
There's something wrong. What's wrong?
没什么不对劲
There's nothing wrong.
是窗户
It's the windows.
你在想这里没窗户
You're thinking there's no windows.
这是密室
It's subterranean.
不舒服 有幽闭恐惧症
It's not cozy, it's claustrophobic.
没有 我没那么想
No. No way. I wasn't thinking that.
我在想：这真酷
I was thinking, "This is really cool."
凯莱布 这房间没有窗户是有原因的
Caleb, there's a reason there are no windows in this room.
- 是吗？- 呃
- There is? - Uh-huh.
这栋建筑物不是住家
This building isn't a house.
这是研究室
It's a research facility.
在这些墙底下 有足够的光纤电缆
Buried in these walls is enough fiber optic cable
能传输到月球 再绕它一圈
to reach the moon and lasso it.
我想告诉你我在做的研究
And I want to talk to you about what I'm researching,
我想和你分享
I want to share it with you.
事实上 我非常想和你分享 想到快发疯了
In fact, I want to share it with you so much, it's eating me up inside.
但我需要你先替我做一件事
But there's something I need you to do for me first.
蓝皮书公司保密合约
"Blue Book non-disclosure agreement."
嗯
Hmm.
花点时间 仔细阅读
Take your time. Read it over.
签署者同意接受
"The signee agrees to regular data audit
无限制的定期资料审核
"with unlimited access,
确认没有泄漏
"to confirm that no disclosure
任何资讯
"of information has taken place
在公开或私人讨论会里
"in public or private forums,
利用各种沟通管道
"using any means of communication,
包括但不限于
"including but not limited
口述
"to that which is disclosed orally
或手写或电子形式
"or in written or electronic form."
我需要律师
I think I need a lawyer.
- 这是标准格式 - 感觉不像标准格式
- It's standard. - It doesn't feel very standard.
好吧 不是标准格式
Okay, it's not standard.
我能怎么说 凯莱布？你不必签
What can I tell you, Caleb? You don't have to sign it.
接下来几天
You know, we can spend the next few days
我们能打打撞球 喝喝酒
just shooting pool, getting drunk together.
建立感情
Bonding.
大约一年后 当你发现自己错过什么时
And when you discover what you've missed out on, in about a year,
你会后悔一辈子
you're gonna regret it for the rest of your life.
做得好
Good call.
所以
So,
你知道什么是图灵测试吗？
do you know what the Turing Test is?
知道
Yeah.
我知道什么是图灵测试
I know what the Turing Test is.
这是人类和电脑的互动
It's when a human interacts with a computer.
如果人类不知道自己和电脑互动
And if the human doesn't know they're interacting with a computer,
就通过测试了
the test is passed.
通过意谓着什么？
And what does a pass tell us?
电脑有人工智能
That the computer has artificial intelligence.
你在研制人工智能？
Are you building an Al?
我已经制造一个了
I've already built one.
接下来几天
And over the next few days,
你在图灵测试里扮演人类的部分
you're gonna be the human component in a Turing Test.
- 不会吧 - 是的 凯莱布 就是你了
- Holy shit. - Yeah, that's right, Caleb. You got it.
因为如果测试通过了
Because if that test is passed,
你 最伟大的科学事件的核心人物
you are dead center of the greatest scientific event in the history of man.
如果你创造了有意识的机械人
If you've created a conscious machine,
那就不是人类的历史
it's not the history of man.
那是神的历史
That's the history of gods.
伊娃：第一期
- 你好 - 你好
- Hello. - Hi.
我是凯莱布
I'm Caleb.
你好 凯莱布
Hello, Caleb.
你有名字吗？
Do you have a name?
有
Yes.
伊娃
Ava.
我很高兴认识你 伊娃
I'm pleased to meet you, Ava.
我也很高兴认识你
I'm pleased to meet you, too.
我以前从没见过别人
I've never met anyone new before.
只有纳森
Only Nathan.
那么我们俩的情况有点类似
Then I guess we're both in quite a similar position.
你以前没见过别人吗？
Haven't you met lots of new people before?
没有跟你一样的人
None like you.
嗯
Hmm.
所以我们得破冰一下
So we need to break the ice.
- 懂我的意思吗？- 懂
- Do you know what I mean by that? - Yes.
什么意思？
What do I mean?
化解最初的社交尴尬
Overcome initial social awkwardness.
所以我们聊聊吧
So let's have a conversation.
好的
Okay.
你想聊什么？
What would you like to have a conversation about?
不如你先自我介绍吧？
Why don't we start with you telling me something about yourself?
你想知道什么？
What would you like to know?
你想到什么就说
Whatever comes into your head.
你已经知道我的名字了
Well, you already know my name.
也看得出来我是机械人
And you can see that I'm a machine.
- 想知道我几岁吗？- 当然
Would you like to know how old I am? Sure.
我是一
I'm one.
什么？
One what?
- 一年还是一天？- 一
- One year or one day? - One.
你何时学会说话 伊娃？
When did you learn how to speak, Ava?
我一直都知道怎么说话
I always knew how to speak,
那很怪吧？
and that's strange, isn't it?
为什么？
Why?
因为语言是学来的
Because language is something that people acquire.
有些人相信语言是与生俱来的
Well, some people believe language exists from birth.
只是学习运用这潜能的
And what is learned is the ability to attach words
句子和结构 你同意吗？
and structure to the latent ability. Do you agree with that?
我不知道
I don't know.
你明天还会来吗 凯莱布？
Will you come back tomorrow, Caleb?
会的
Yes.
很好
Good.
老天 她好迷人
Oh, man, she's fascinating.
跟她说话时 就像是…
When you talk to her, you're just...
镜中奇缘
Through the looking glass.
"镜中奇缘" 天啊
"Through the looking glass." Wow.
你真会说话 凯莱布 引用名言佳句
You're good with words, Caleb. You're quotable.
其实那是别人引用的
Actually, that's someone else's quote.
我写下了 你构思出来的另一句话
You know, I wrote down that other line you came up with.
关于
The one about how
我发明了有意识的机械人
if I've invented a machine with consciousness,
我不是人 我是神
I'm not a man, I'm God.
我想那不是…
I don't think that's exactly what I...
我只是觉得 老天 那太棒了
I just thought, "Fuck, man, that is so good."
等这故事公诸于世时
When we get to tell the story. You know?
我转头看凯莱布
I turned to Caleb,
他抬头看着我说
and he looked up at me and he said,
你不是人 你是神
"You're not a man, you're God."
对 但我没那么说
Yeah, but I didn't say that.
所以…
So...
总之
Anyway.
她让你惊叹
You're impressed.
对 对
Yes. Yes.
- 虽然… - 虽然？
- Although... - Although?
你惊叹还有条件？
There's a qualification to you being impressed?
没有 对她没有任何条件
No, there's no qualification to her.
只是图灵测试
Uh, it's just in the Turing Test,
机械人不该被测试员看到
the machine should be hidden from the examiner.
不 我们远远超过那点
No, no, no, we're way past that.
若不让你看到伊娃
If I hid Ava from you,
只听到声音 她会通过人类测试
so you just heard her voice, she would pass for human.
真正的测试是让你看到她是机械人
The real test is to show you that she's a robot
然后看你是否仍觉得她有意识
and then see if you still feel she has consciousness.
嗯
Mmm.
对 你可能是对的
Yeah, I think you're probably right.
她的语言能力很不可思议
Her language abilities, they're incredible.
系统是随机的 对吧？
The system is stochastic. Right?
非决定性的
It's non-deterministic.
刚开始我认为
At first I thought she was mapping
她把内在语义编排成树状句法
from internal semantic form to syntactic tree-structure
然后得到线性句子
and then getting linearized words.
但后来我渐渐明白 这是混合的模式
But then I started to realize the model was some kind of hybrid.
凯莱布
Caleb.
不是吗？
No?
我明白你希望我解释伊娃的运作
I understand that you want me to explain how Ava works.
但很抱歉 我没办法那么做
But I'm sorry, I'm not gonna be able to do that.
说来听听 我对高阶的抽象概念很拿手
Try me. I'm hot on high-level abstraction.
不是因为我认为你太愚昧
It's not because I think you're too dumb.
而是因为我想和你喝啤酒聊天
It's because I want to have a beer and a conversation with you.
不是开研讨会
Not a seminar.
对 抱歉
Yeah. Sorry.
不 没关系 你很好
No, it's okay. You're all right.
只是…
Just...
回答我这个问题
Answer me this.
你对她有何感觉？
How do you feel about her?
不是逻辑上的
Nothing analytical.
而是你的感觉？
Just how do you feel?
我觉得
I feel...
她真的很神奇
that she's fucking amazing.
老弟
Dude.
干杯
Cheers.
真是的
Damn it.
搞什么？
What the fuck?
断电 启动备用电源
Power cut. Backup power activated.
封锁所有设备 直到主电源恢复供电
Full facility lock-down until main generator is restored.
不会吧
You're kidding me.
封锁所有设备 直到主电源恢复供电
Full facility lock-down until main generator is restored.
恢复供电
Power restored.
有人吗？
Hello?
请插入门卡
Please insert keycard.
你没有权限使用电话
You don't have access to use the phone.
嘿
Hey.
抱歉 但你要理解 你知道伊娃这案子
Sorry, but you understand, though, given Ava,
而你算是个未知人物
and you being kind of an unknown.
我是说 一个好人
I mean, a great guy.
一拍即合的好伙伴
Instant pals, and so on.
你要打给谁？
Who are you gonna call?
哦
Oh.
不知道 没有人吧
I don't know. No one, really.
- 魔鬼克星 - 什么？
- Ghostbusters. - What?
你要打给谁？魔鬼克星 那是…
Who are you gonna call? Ghostbusters. It's a...
那是一部电影
It's a movie, man.
你不知道那部电影？
You don't know that movie?
鬼帮丹·艾克洛德做性服务
A ghost gives Dan Aykroyd oral sex.
我只是好奇怎么使用电话
I was just wondering how the phone worked.
如此而已
That's all.
你这时候醒来做什么？
So what are you doing awake at this time?
来加入派对吗？
You come to join the party?
我的房间出了点状况
Uh, something happened in my room.
好像断电了
Some kind of power cut.
所以我来看怎么回事
So I came to see what's going on.
断电 对
The power cuts, yeah.
最近常常断电
We've been getting those recently. Um...
我在想办法解决
I'm working on it.
我没办法打开我的房门
I couldn't open the door to my bedroom.
那是安全措施
That's a security measure.
自动封锁 不然的话
Automatic lock-down. Otherwise,
任何人都能利用切断电源 闯进屋里
anybody could just open the place up by disabling the juice.
若再发生 别紧张 好吗？
If it happens again, relax. Okay?
当然
Sure.
祝你有个美梦
Sweet dreams.
哦
Oh.
嘿
Hey.
- 嘿 伙计 - 早上好
- Hey, man. - Good morning.
早上好 抱歉 我得派京子把你吵醒
Good morning. Sorry I had to send Kyoko to wake you,
我只是不想虚度今日
but I didn't want too much of the day to slip by.
对 我了解 这是好事 谢谢
Yeah, I know. It was a good thing. Thanks.
她很迷人吧？
She's some alarm clock, huh?
让你一早就很亢奋
Gets you right up in the morning.
第二天 准备好了吗？
So Day 2. You ready?
有何计划？说来听听
What's the plan? Hit me.
对 我不确定
Yeah, well, I'm not sure.
我还在思考测试形式
I'm still trying to, uh, figure the examination formats.
哦
Uh-huh.
对 我觉得
Yeah, it feels like
透过对话测试伊娃是个死胡同
testing Ava through conversation is kind of a closed loop.
- 死胡同？- 对
- It's a closed loop? - Yeah.
就像只用下棋来测试电脑国际象棋
Like testing a chess computer by only playing chess.
不然你怎么测试电脑国际象棋？
How else do you test a chess computer?
看情况
Well, it depends.
你可以跟它下棋
You know, I mean, you can play it
看它是否下对棋 但是…
to find out if it makes good moves, but, uh...
但是那样无法测出
But that won't tell you if it knows
它是否知道这是在下棋
that it's playing chess.
也无法测出 它是否知道什么是下棋
And it won't tell you if it knows what chess is.
呃 因此这是区分模拟和真实
Uh-huh. So it's simulation versus actual.
对 对
Yes. Yeah.
我认为把这两者区分出来
And I think being able to differentiate between those two
才是你要我执行的图灵测试
is the Turing Test you want me to perform.
帮我个忙 别管教科书上的方法
Look, do me a favor. Lay off the textbook approach.
我只想得到简单问题的简单答案
I just want simple answers to simple questions.
昨天我问你对她的感觉
Yesterday I asked you how you felt about her
你给了我好答案
and you gave me a great answer.
现在问题是
Now the question is,
她对你有何感觉？
how does she feel about you?
伊娃：第二期
你觉得如何？
What do you think?
你在画什么？
What is it a drawing of?
你不知道吗？
Don't you know?
- 不知道 - 还以为你会告诉我
- No. - I thought you would tell me.
你不知道吗？
Don't you know?
我每天画画
I do drawings every day.
但我从不知道那是什么
But I never know what they're of.
你不试着画具体一点的东西吗？
Are you not trying to sketch something specific?
例如一个物体或人？
Like an object or a person?
也许你能试试
Maybe you could try.
好吧
Okay.
我该画什么物体？
What object should I draw?
随你 由你决定
Whatever you want. It's your decision.
为什么由我决定？
Why is it my decision?
我很想看你会选择什么
I'm interested to see what you'll choose.
你想当我的朋友吗？
Do you want to be my friend?
当然
Of course.
有可能吗？
Will it be possible?
为何不可能？
Why would it not be?
我们的谈话是单向的
Our conversations are one-sided.
你谨慎地提问并研究我的反应
You ask circumspect questions and study my responses.
对
Yes.
你了解我
You learn about me
我却一点也不了解你
and I learn nothing about you.
那不是友谊的基础
That's not a foundation on which friendships are based.
所以呢？你要我谈谈自己？
So what? You want me to talk about myself?
对
Yes.
这个嘛…
Where...
好吧 我该从何说起？
Okay, where do I start?
由你决定
It's your decision.
我很想看你会选择什么
I'm interested to see what you'll choose.
嗯
Hmm.
好吧 伊娃
Okay, Ava.
这个嘛
Well,
你知道我的名字
you know my name.
- 知道 - 我26岁
- Yes. - I'm 26.
我在纳森的公司上班
I work at Nathan's company.
你知道他的公司吗？
Do you know what his company is?
蓝皮书公司
Blue Book.
以维根斯坦的笔记命名
Named after Wittgenstein's notes.
这公司是世上最受欢迎的 网络搜寻引擎
It's the world's most popular internet search engine,
平均处理全球百分之94的 网络搜寻需求
processing an average of 94% of all internet search requests.
完全正确
That's exactly right.
你住哪 凯莱布？
Where do you live, Caleb?
长岛的布鲁克海文
Brookhaven, Long Island.
那里好吗？
Is it nice there?
还好
It's okay.
我住在公寓里 有点小
I got an apartment. It's kind of small.
非常小
It's very small.
不过到公司只要走五分钟
But, uh, it's a five-minute walk to the office
到海边也只要走五分钟
and a five-minute walk to the ocean,
我喜欢那样
which I like.
你结婚了吗？
Are you married?
呃
Um...
没有
No.
你是单身吗？
Is your status single?
对
Yes.
你的家人呢？
What about your family?
我在俄勒冈州波特兰长大
I grew up in Portland, Oregon.
没有兄弟姊妹
No brothers or sisters.
我父母都是高中老师
My parents were both high school teachers.
如果我们俩再熟一点
And if we're getting to know each other,
我大概会告诉你 他们俩死了
I guess I should tell you they're both dead.
在我15岁时车祸身亡
Car crash when I was 15.
事实上 我也在车里
In fact, I was in the car with them.
后座
Back seat.
前座情况最严重
But it was the front that got the worst of it.
我很遗憾
I'm sorry.
没关系的
It's all right.
后来我在医院躺了很久
I spent a long time in the hospital afterward.
将近一年
Like nearly a year.
然后我喜欢上编写程序
And I got into coding.
等我上大学时 我就很高级了
And by the time I got to college, I was pretty advanced.
一名高级的程序员
An advanced programmer.
是的
Yes.
就像纳森
Like Nathan.
对
Yes.
不对
No.
不一样
It's different.
纳森13岁时 就编写了蓝皮书的基础码
Nathan wrote the Blue Book base code when he was 13.
如果你懂得编程
Which, if you understand code,
他的成就形同莫札特
what he did was like Mozart or something.
你喜欢莫札特吗？
Do you like Mozart?
我喜欢流行尖端乐团
I like Depeche Mode.
你喜欢纳森吗？
Do you like Nathan?
当然喜欢
Yes, of course.
- 纳森是你的朋友吗？- 我的朋友？
- Is Nathan your friend? - My friend?
我…对 我希望
I... Yeah, I hope so.
好朋友？
A good friend?
呃 对
Um, yeah.
不 不 不是好朋友
Well, no, no, no, I mean, not a good friend.
好朋友是…
A good friend is, uh...
我们才刚认识
We only just met each other, you know.
因此需要时间才能…
So it takes time to be able to, um...
互相了解吧
To get to know each other, I guess.
断电 启动备用电源
Power cut. Backup power activated.
凯莱布
Caleb.
你错了
You're wrong.
什么错了？
Wrong about what?
纳森
Nathan.
哪方面？
In what way?
他不是你的朋友
He isn't your friend.
你说什么？
Excuse me?
抱歉 伊娃 我不懂
I'm sorry, Ava, I don't understand.
你不该相信他
You shouldn't trust him.
你不该相信他说的话
You shouldn't trust anything he says.
恢复供电
Power restored.
如果列出我们俩都熟悉的
And if we made a list of books
书或艺术品清单
or works of art which we both know,
就能建立理想的对话基础
it would form the ideal basis of a discussion.
可以吗？
Is that okay?
凯莱布？
Caleb?
嗯哼
Mmm-hmm.
好
Yeah.
很好
Good.
谢谢
Thank you.
真是的 你在耍我吗？
Oh, shit! Are you fucking kidding me?
- 有洒到你吗？- 没有…
- Did it get on you? - No, no, it's, uh...
没关系 我来
It's all right. I got it.
跟她说话是浪费时间
Dude, you're wasting your time talking to her.
她不懂英文 直接给她餐巾
She doesn't understand English. Just give her the napkin.
抱歉
Sorry.
这就像防漏的防火墙
It's like a firewall against leaks.
表示我吃晚餐时能聊商业机密
It means I can talk trade secrets over dinner
而不会被传出去
and know it'll go no further.
也表示她笨手笨脚地
It also means that I can't tell her that
把酒洒在我客人身上时
I'm pissed when she's so fucking clumsy
我没办法跟她说我很生气
that she spills wine over my house guest.
她应该知道你生气了
I think she gets that you're pissed.
是吗？很好 因为我很生气
Yeah? Good. Because I am pissed.
嘿 京子
Hey, Kyoko.
走开
Go-go.
真诡异
It's funny.
你知道的
You know.
不管多有钱
No matter how rich you get,
鸟事还是会发生 躲也躲不掉
shit goes wrong. You can't insulate yourself from it.
我以前以为躲不掉的是死亡和税
I used to think it was death and taxes you couldn't avoid,
但其实是死亡和鸟事
but it's actually death and shit.
比如说断电
It's like these power cuts.
你不会相信 我在电力系统上花了多少钱
You would not believe how much I spent on the generator system,
但每天还是出错
but I keep getting failures every day.
- 你知道为何断电吗？- 不知道
- Do you know why they happen? - No.
系统应该是坚不可摧的
The system was supposed to be bulletproof,
但显然安装的人搞砸了什么
but obviously the guys that installed it fucked something up.
不能请他们回来修理吗？
Can't you just get them to come back?
不行 这里有太多机密
No. There's too much classified stuff here.
等他们修理完后 我得杀人灭口
So after the job was done, I just had them all killed.
总之
Anyway.
敬你的第二天 伙伴
Here's to your second day, buddy.
干杯
Cheers.
所以情况如何？你有什么要报告的吗？
So how did it go? What do you have to report?
你看到今天的情况了 不是吗？
You saw how the day went, didn't you?
我相信
I mean, I assume you're, uh,
你透过监视器观看
watching on the CCTV.
当然 但我想听听你的想法
Sure. But I want to hear your take on it.
对 今天伊娃做了一件有趣的事
Yeah, there was one interesting thing that happened with Ava today.
- 是吗？- 是
- Yeah? - Yeah.
她说了一个笑话
She made a joke.
对 她用你的话回你
Right. When she threw your line back at you.
关于想看她选择什么
About being interested to see what she'd choose.
对 我也注意到了
Yeah, I noticed that, too.
对 这让我觉得…
Yeah, and it got me thinking, it's, uh...
在某方面 这是我目前 在她身上看到最棒的人工智能
In a way, it's the best indication of Al that I've seen in her so far.
这相当地复杂
It's discretely complicated.
就像是… 经过思考的
It's like, um... It's kind of non-autistic.
什么意思？
What do you mean?
只有在了解她自己和我的心智下
She could only do that with an awareness of her own mind,
才能做到那点
and also an awareness of mine.
她也了解你
Oh, she's aware of you all right.
断电部分呢？
And what about the power cut?
- 什么？- 断电
- Sorry? - The power cut.
只有那部分我没看到
It's the only part that I couldn't see.
摄影机当掉了 没有声音和画面
Cameras fail, I lose audio, the works.
所以发生什么事？
So what happened?
没事
Nothing.
没事？她没提到任何事吗？
Nothing? She didn't remark on it at all?
没有
No.
不算有
Not really.
哦
Oh.
嘿
Hey.
你想看点酷的东西吗？
You want to see something cool?
伊娃是在这里建造的
This is where Ava was created.
去吧 去看看
Go ahead. Take a look.
抱歉
Sorry.
你知道我解决多少麻烦
If you knew the trouble I had
才能让人工智能 理解并复制脸部表情吧
getting an Al to read and duplicate facial expressions.
知道我怎么解决的吗？
You know how I cracked it?
我一点也不知道你怎么做到的
I don't know how you did any of this.
每支手机都有
Every cell phone, just about,
一个麦克风 相机 还有传输资料的方法
has a microphone, camera and a means to transmit data.
因此我开启全球所有的麦克风和相机
So I turned on every microphone and camera across the entire fucking planet
透过蓝皮书移转资料
and I redirected the data through Blue Book. Boom!
无限的声音和表情资源
Limitless resource of vocal and facial interaction.
你骇进全球的手机？
You hacked the world's cell phones?
是的 所有制造商 也都知道我在做这种事
Yeah. And all the manufacturers knew I was doing it, too.
但他们不能指控我
But they couldn't accuse me
因为他们本身也在做这种事
without admitting they were doing it themselves.
在这里
Here,
我们有她的心智
we have her mind.
组织胶体
Structured gel.
我必须远离电路系统
I had to get away from circuitry.
我需要某个
I needed something that could
在分子层面上能反覆编排的物体
arrange and rearrange on a molecular level,
必要时还能保留它的形体
but keep its form when required.
既能保留记忆
Holding for memories.
也能随思考改变
Shifting for thoughts.
这是你的硬件？
This is your hardware?
湿件
Wetware.
软件呢？
And the, uh, software?
我相信你猜得到
Well, I'm sure you can guess.
蓝皮书
Blue Book.
这就是搜寻引擎奇特之处
Here's the weird thing about search engines.
就像是
It was like
在内燃机还没发明的时代 发现石油
striking oil in a world that hadn't invented internal combustion.
太多原物料 没人知道如何利用
Too much raw material. Nobody knew what to do with it.
我的竞争对手
You see, my competitors,
专注于牟取暴利
they were fixated on sucking it up
透过购物和社群媒体
and monetizing via shopping and social media.
他们认为搜寻引擎是人们思考的事物
They thought that search engines were a map of what people were thinking.
但其实那是人们思考的方式
But actually they were a map of how people were thinking.
冲动
Impulse.
反应
Response.
流动
Fluid.
不完美
Imperfect.
模式
Patterned.
杂乱
Chaotic.
伊娃：第三期
我画了具体的画
I drew the picture of something specific.
如你要求的
As you asked.
你说过你很想看我会画什么
You said it would be interesting to see what I would draw.
有趣吗？
Is it interesting?
是的 很有趣
Yes. It is.
你没离开过这栋楼吧？
You've never been outside this building?
没有
No.
你没走到外面过？
You've never walked outside?
我没离开过现在这个房间
I've never been outside the room I am in now.
如果你到外面 你会去哪？
Where would you go if you did go outside?
我不确定
I'm not sure.
有好多选择
There are so many options.
也许到城市里 繁忙的人行道和十字路口
Maybe a busy pedestrian and traffic intersection in a city.
十字路口？
A traffic intersection?
那是坏主意吗？
Is that a bad idea?
不是
No. Uh...
这不是我预期的
It wasn't what I was expecting.
十字路口代表人类生活
A traffic intersection would provide a concentrated
专注却多变的一面
but shifting view of human life.
人们会留意
People watching.
对
Yes.
嗯
Mmm.
我们可以一起去
We could go together.
这是约会
It's a date.
我想给你看一样东西
There's something else I wanted to show you.
好的
Okay.
也许你会觉得很蠢
You might think it's stupid.
不管是什么 我不会那么觉得
I don't think I will. Whatever it is.
那就闭上眼睛
Then close your eyes.
好的
Okay.
现在张开眼睛
Now open your eyes.
我看来如何？
How do I look?
你看来
You look...
很好
good.
我会穿这样约会
This is what I'd wear on our date.
好 先去十字路口
Right. First a traffic intersection.
再去看表演
Then maybe a show.
我希望我们能去约会
I'd like us to go on a date.
对 对
Yeah. Yeah.
会很好玩的
It would be fun.
你被我吸引了吗？
Are you attracted to me?
- 什么？- 你被我吸引了吗？
- What? - Are you attracted to me?
你在暗示我是的
You give me indications that you are.
- 是吗？- 对
- I do? - Yes.
- 怎么说？- 微表情
- How? - Micro expressions.
微表情
Micro expressions.
你盯着我的眼睛和嘴唇的方式
The way your eyes fix on my eyes and lips.
时而抓住我的眼神
The way you hold my gaze
时而没有
or don't.
我们没在一起时 你想我吗？
Do you think about me when we aren't together?
有时在晚上
Sometimes at night,
我在想你是否透过摄影机看我
I'm wondering if you're watching me on the cameras.
我希望你有
And I hope you are.
现在你的微表情正传送着不安
Now your micro expressions are telegraphing discomfort.
我不确定你称那为微表情
I am not sure you'd call them micro.
我不想让你感到不自在
I don't want to make you feel uncomfortable.
我有个问题
I got a question.
- 好的 - 你为何给她性特征？
- Okay. - Why did you give her sexuality?
人工智能不需要性别
An AI doesn't need a gender.
她可以是个灰盒子
She could have been a gray box.
其实我认为那不是事实
Hmm. Actually, I don't think that's true.
你能举个例子
Can you give an example of consciousness,
人类或动物在任何层面上
at any level, human or animal,
少了性还有意识存在的吗？
that exists without a sexual dimension?
性是为了繁殖后代演变而来的
They have sexuality as an evolutionary reproductive need.
灰盒子和灰盒子
What imperative does a gray box have
有什么好互动的？
to interact with another gray box?
少了互动 意识能存在吗？
Can consciousness exist without interaction?
总之 性很有趣
Anyway, sexuality is fun, man.
既然存在 为何不好好享受
If you're gonna exist, why not enjoy it?
怎样？你想抹煞她
What? You want to remove the chance
恋爱和性爱的机会？
of her falling in love and fucking?
回答你真正的问题
And in answer to your real question,
她能做那档事
you bet she can fuck.
什么？
What?
在她双腿之间有个开口
In between her legs, there's an opening,
里头有高敏感应器
with a concentration of sensors.
正确地使用
You engage them in the right way,
能产生欢愉
creates a pleasure response.
如果你想上她
So if you wanted to screw her,
技术上来说 你可以
mechanically speaking, you could.
她也很享受
And she'd enjoy it.
那不是我真正的问题
That wasn't my real question.
好吧 抱歉
Oh, okay. Sorry.
我真正的问题是
My real question was,
你给她性能力
did you give her sexuality
是为了分散注意力吗？
as a diversion tactic?
我不懂
I don't follow.
就像魔术师身旁的性感女助理
Like a stage magician with a hot assistant.
利用性感机械人 模糊你对人工智能的判断力？
So a hot robot who clouds your ability to judge her Al?
没错 所以…
Exactly. So...
你设计程序让她对我调情吗？
Did you program her to flirt with me?
是的话 算作弊吗？
If I did, would that be cheating?
不算吗？
Wouldn't it?
凯莱布 你喜欢哪种类型？
Caleb, what's your type?
- 女孩吗？- 不 沙拉酱
- Of girl? - No, of salad dressing.
对 女孩 你喜欢哪种女孩？
Yeah, of girl. What's your type of girl?
别回答了 就说黑妞吧
You know what? Don't even answer that. Let's say it's black chicks.
那是你的爱好
Okay, that's your thing.
为了便于讨论 假设那是你的爱好
For the sake of argument, that's your thing, okay?
为什么那是你的爱好？
Why is that your thing?
因为你仔细分析过所有的人种
Because you did a detailed analysis of all racial types
并用记点积分制交叉比对过吗？
and you cross-referenced that analysis with a points-based system?
不
No!
你就是喜欢黑妞
You're just attracted to black chicks.
外在刺激累积而来的结果
A consequence of accumulated external stimuli
也许你根本没注意 她们就占据你的心了
that you probably didn't even register as they registered with you.
你到底有没有设计程序 让她喜欢我？
Did you program her to like me, or not?
我把她设计成异性恋
I programmed her to be heterosexual.
如同你被设计成异性恋
Just like you were programmed to be heterosexual.
没人把我设计成异性恋
Nobody programmed me to be straight.
你决定当异性恋吗？拜托
You decided to be straight? Please.
你当然是被设计的
Of course you were programmed.
被大自然或教育 或两者
By nature or nurture, or both.
老实说 凯莱布 你开始惹恼我了
And to be honest, Caleb, you're starting to annoy me now,
因为你说这番话是出自不安
because this is your insecurity talking.
不是出自大脑
This is not your intellect.
跟我来
Come with me.
你知道这家伙吧？
You know this guy, right?
- 杰克森波洛克 - 对
- Jackson Pollock. Jackson Pollock. - That's right.
滴画画家
The drip painter.
他放空自己
Okay. He let his mind go blank,
双手才能好好发挥
and his hand go where it wanted.
不是有意的 也不是随机的
Not deliberate, not random.
而是两者之间
Some place in between.
他们称之为无意识艺术
They called it automatic art.
让我们把这当成《星际争霸战》吧？
Let's make this like Star Trek, okay?
运用智慧
Engage intellect.
什么意思？
Excuse me?
我是寇克 你的脑是曲速引擎
I'm Kirk. Your head's the warp drive.
运用智慧
Engage intellect.
如果波洛克反过来挑战呢？
What if Pollock had reversed the challenge?
万一他不再无思考地创造艺术
What if instead of making art
反而说：知道吗？
without thinking, he said, "You know what?
我没办法画
"I can't paint anything,
除非知道自己到底为何而画
"unless I know exactly why I'm doing it."
那会怎样？
What would have happened?
他永远无法创造伟大画作
He never would have made a single mark.
对 这才是我的好伙伴
Yes! You see, there's my guy, there's my buddy,
经过思考才开口说话
who thinks before he opens his mouth.
他永远无法创造伟大画作
He never would have made a single mark.
挑战不是无意识的行为
The challenge is not to act automatically.
这是去寻找一个有意识的行为
It's to find an action that is not automatic.
从画画到呼吸到说话
From painting, to breathing, to talking,
到上床
to fucking.
到恋爱
To falling in love.
郑重说明 伊娃不是假装喜欢你
And for the record, Ava's not pretending to like you.
她的调情不是一种演算法 以欺骗你为目的
And her flirting isn't an algorithm to fake you out.
除了我之外 你是她认识的第一个男人
You're the first man she's met that isn't me.
我就像她爸 对吧？
And I'm like her dad, right?
你能怪她喜欢你吗？
Can you blame her for getting a crush on you?
不 你不能
No, you can't.
伊娃：第四期
我在大学时 修了一学期的人工智能学
When I was in college, I did a semester on Al theory.
他们给了我们一个思想实验
There was a thought experiment they gave us.
称之为在黑白房间里的玛莉
It's called "Mary in the Black and White Room."
玛莉是科学家
Mary is a scientist,
她专攻颜色
and her specialist subject is color.
她了解跟颜色有关的一切
She knows everything there is to know about it.
波长
The wavelengths.
对神经系统的影响
The neurological effects.
颜色具有的每种特性
Every possible property that color can have.
但她住在黑白房间里
But she lives in a black and white room.
她在那里出生长大
She was born there and raised there.
她只能透过黑白监视器
And she can only observe the outside world
观察外面的世界
on a black and white monitor.
然后有一天 有人打开门
And then one day someone opens the door.
玛莉走出去
And Mary walks out.
她看到蓝天
And she sees a blue sky.
那一刻 她学到所有文献
And at that moment, she learns something
都无法告诉她的事物
that all her studies couldn't tell her.
她学到看见颜色的感觉
She learns what it feels like to see color.
思想实验是在向学生证明
The thought experiment was to show the students
电脑和人类心智之间的差异
the difference between a computer and a human mind.
电脑是在黑白房间里的玛莉
The computer is Mary in the black and white room.
当她走出去时 她才是人类
The human is when she walks out.
你知道我是来测试你的吗？
Did you know that I was brought here to test you?
不知道
No.
你想我为何在这里？
Why did you think I was here?
我不知道 我没质疑过
I didn't know. I didn't question it.
我是来测试你是否有意识
I'm here to test if you have a consciousness,
或你是否只是在模拟
or if you're just simulating one.
纳森不确定你是否有意识
Nathan isn't sure if you have one or not.
那让你有何感觉？
How does that make you feel?
那让我觉得悲伤
It makes me feel sad.
断电 启动备用电源
Power cut. Back-up power activated.
为何告诉我 我不该信任纳森？
Why did you tell me I shouldn't trust Nathan?
因为他说谎
Because he tells lies.
关于什么？
Lies about what?
所有的一切
Everything.
包括断电吗？
Including the power cuts?
什么意思？
What do you mean?
你不觉得 他很可能在监视我们吗？
Don't you think it's possible that he's watching us?
此刻？
Right now?
断电是故意安排的
That the blackouts are orchestrated,
他才能看到
so he can see how we behave
我们以为没被监视时的行为
when we think we're unobserved.
我透过电磁盘帮自己充电
I charge my batteries via induction plates.
如果我让电流逆转 电力就会过载
If I reverse the power flow, it overloads the system.
断电是你造成的？
You're causing the cuts?
我们才能看到没被监视时的行为
So we can see how we behave when we're unobserved.
还不错吧？
Not bad, huh?
是啊
Yeah.
能谈谈你一直在欺骗我的谎言吗？
Can we talk about the lies you've been spinning me?
什么谎言？
What lies?
我没抽中头奖
I didn't win a competition.
我不是
I wasn't
被抽中的 我是被选中的
part of a lottery. I was selected.
当我停下来思考时 就很明显了
It's obvious, once I stop to think.
你为何要随机抽一名测试员
Why would you randomly select an examiner
来做图灵测试？
for the Turing Test?
你可以找某个突然出现在 你家大门口的政府官员
You could have had some bean counter turn up at your front door.
修冷气的工人
The guy who fixes the air-conditioning.
抽奖是个烟幕
The competition was a smokescreen.
我不想让任何人知道 我在这里做什么
I didn't want anyone to know what I was doing here,
或是为何找你
or why I required you.
为何找我？
Why me?
我需要能问正确问题的人
I needed someone that would ask the right questions.
因此我搜寻了一下 找到了公司里
So I did a search and I found the most
最优秀的程序员
talented coder in my company.
别把这视为欺骗
You know, instead of seeing this as a deception,
你该把这视为证明
you should see it as proof.
- 证明什么？- 拜托 凯莱布
- Proof of what? - Come on, Caleb.
你以为我不知道聪明的感觉吗？
You don't think I know what it's like to be smart?
比所有人都聪明 拔得头筹
Smarter than everyone else. Jockeying for position.
你相当优秀 老弟
You got the light on you, man.
不是抽中的 是选中的
Not lucky. Chosen.
京子
Kyoko.
纳森在哪？
Where's Nathan?
老天 你真的不会说英文？
Jesus Christ. You really don't speak a word of English?
搞什么？
What the fuck?
不 不 不
No, no, no. No!
住手
Stop!
不 别那么做 你不必那么做
No, no, don't do that. Don't do that. You don't have to do that.
你在做什么？
What are you doing?
我告诉过你 跟她说话是浪费时间
I told you, you're wasting your time talking to her.
不过跟她跳舞
However, you would not be wasting your time,
不会浪费时间
if you were dancing with her.
去吧 跟她跳舞 跟她跳舞
Go ahead, dance with her. Dance with her.
不要吗？你不喜欢跳舞？
No? You don't like dancing?
她喜欢
She does.
来吧 伙伴
Come on, buddy.
经过一整天的图灵测试 你得放松一下
After a long day of Turing Tests, you gotta unwind.
你把伊娃怎么了？
What were you doing with Ava?
什么？
What?
你弄坏她的画
You tore up her picture.
我还要弄坏舞池咧 老弟
I'm gonna tear up the fucking dance floor, dude.
看看吧
Check it out.
来吧 凯莱布
Come on, Caleb.
哦 万物都在旋转
Oh! Everything's spinning.
那是因为你醉了
It's because you're drunk.
不 这叫相对论 万物都在旋转
No, it's called relativity. Everything is spinning.
只是喝醉让它更糟
It's just being drunk makes it worse.
我不进去了
I'm not going in there.
关灯
Lights.
伊娃：第五期
今天 我要测试你
Today, I'm going to test you.
测试我？
Test me?
请记住 你在接受测试时
And please remember, while you're taking the test,
如果你说谎
that if you lie,
我会知道
I will know.
好的
Oh. Right.
问题一
Question one.
你最喜欢的颜色？
What's your favorite color?
- 红色 - 说谎
- Red. - Lie.
- 说谎？- 对 说谎
- Lie? - Yes. Lie.
那…
Then...
那我最喜欢什么颜色？
Then what is my favorite color?
我不知道
I don't know.
但不是红色
But it isn't red.
好吧 我懂了
Okay, I get it. I guess,
由于我不是六岁 我不知道自己有喜欢的颜色
seeing as I'm not six, I don't really have a favorite color.
这样回答好多了
Better answer.
问题二
Question two.
你最早的记忆？
What's your earliest memory?
其实是幼稚园的记忆
Well, actually, it's a memory of kindergarten.
- 有个小孩… - 说谎
- There was a kid... - Lie.
- 是吗？- 对
- Really? - Yes.
呃
Um...
好吧 所以还有更早的记忆
All right. So there is a kind of an earlier memory.
只是一个声音
It's just a sound.
还有天空
And sky.
或者可能是蓝色
Or maybe blue.
我想声音是我母亲的声音
I think the sound is my mother's voice.
问题三
Question three.
你是好人吗？
Are you a good person?
哦
Oh.
不会吧
Holy shit.
能停止测试吗？
Look, can we stop the test?
你是个会走路的测谎仪
You're a walking lie detector,
我刚明白这根本是个禁区
and I just realized this is a fucking minefield.
不行 不能停止
No! We can't stop.
你是好人吗？
Are you a good person?
我想是吧
Yeah. I think so.
问题四
Question four.
如果我没通过你的测试 我会怎样？
What will happen to me if I fail your test?
- 伊娃… - 会很糟吗？
- Ava... - Will it be bad?
我不知道
I don't know.
你认为我可能会
Do you think I might be switched off,
因为功能不佳而被关掉吗？
because I don't function as well as I'm supposed to?
伊娃 我不知道这问题的答案
Ava, I don't know the answer to your question.
这不是由我决定的
It's not up to me.
为什么由别人决定？
Why is it up to anyone?
有人测试你 并可能把你关掉吗？
Do you have people who test you and might switch you off?
- 没有 我没有 - 那我为什么有？
- No, I don't. - Then why do I?
断电 启动备用电源
Power cut. Backup power activated.
我想和你在一起
I wanna be with you.
问题五
Question five.
你想和我在一起吗？
Do you want to be with me?
你为何制造伊娃？
Why did you make Ava?
真怪的问题
That's an odd question.
如果你能 你不会吗？
Wouldn't you, if you could?
也许吧
Maybe.
我不知道
I don't know.
我在问你为何制造
I'm asking why you did it.
高度人工智能的问世
Look, the arrival of strong artificial intelligence
在未来几十年是必然的
has been inevitable for decades.
变数是"何时" 而不是"如果"
The variable was "when," not "if."
因此伊娃的制造 不是决定 而是发展
So I don't see Ava as a decision, just an evolution.
我认为下个型号
I think it's the next model
会有真正的突破
that's gonna be the real breakthrough.
独一无二的
The singularity.
下个型号？
Next model?
继伊娃之后
After Ava.
我不知道伊娃之后 会有新的型号
I didn't know there was gonna be a model after Ava.
怎么？你以为她是唯一一个？
Yeah, why? You thought she was a one-off?
不 我知道一定有很多原型 所以我…
No, I knew there must have been prototypes. So I...
我知道她不是第一个 但我以为是最后一个
I knew she wasn't the first, but I thought maybe the last.
伊娃不是只存在 你或我之间的唯一个体
Well, Ava doesn't exist in isolation any more than you or me.
她是连续型号
She's part of a continuum.
第9.6版之类的
So Version 9.6 and so on.
一版比一版还优秀
And each time they get a little bit better.
你做新型号时 怎么处理旧型号？
When you make a new model, what do you do with the old one?
这个 我 呃
Well, I, uh,
我下载思维 取出数据
download the mind, unpack the data.
加入我一直在写的新程序
Add in the new routines I've been writing.
最后进行部分格式化 清除记忆
And to do that you end up partially formatting, so the memories go.
但身体会留下来
But the body survives.
伊娃的身体做得很好
And Ava's body is a good one.
你替伊娃难过？
You feel bad for Ava?
替自己难过吧
Feel bad for yourself, man.
将来有一天 人工智能会回顾我们
One day the AIs are gonna look back on us
就像我们回顾非洲平原的化石一样
the same way we look at fossil skeletons in the plains of Africa.
直立猿人 住在尘土里
An upright ape, living in dust,
使用简单的语言和工具
with crude language and tools.
最后全都灭绝
All set for extinction.
我成为摧毁世界的死神
"I am become Death, the destroyer of worlds."
你又来了 名言佳句大师
There you go again, Mr. Quotable.
你才又来了 这不是我的名言佳句
There you go again. It's not my quote.
这是奥本海默说的 在他制造了原子弹后
It's what Oppenheimer said after he made the atomic bomb.
原子弹 对 我知道
The atomic bomb. Yeah, I know what it is, dude.
嘿
Hey.
我们该再倒一杯了
I'd say we're about due a refill.
干杯
Bottoms up.
在战场上 在森林里
"In battle, in the forest,
在断崖边
"on the precipice of the mountain.
在…
"On the...
浩翰的黑海里
"The great dark sea.
在睡梦中 在困惑中
"In sleep, in confusion,
在羞愧的深渊里
"in the depths of shame.
以前行善积德让他逢凶化吉
"The good deeds a man has done before defend him."
"The good deeds a man has done before defends him."
以前行善积德
"The good deeds a man has done before
让他逢凶化吉
"defends him."
确实如此
It is what it is.
这是普罗米修斯
It's Promethean, man.
我的天
Jesus Christ.
你今天觉得如何？
How are you feeling today?
你为何不让我出去？
Why won't you let me out?
我已经跟你说过原因了
I already told you why.
因为你很特别
Because you're very special.
为何不让我出去？
Why won't you let me out?
要再来一次吗？
Are we gonna do this again?
为何不让我出去？
Why won't you let me out?
哦 见鬼 我的卡呢？
Oh, fuck. Where's my card?
该死
Damn it!
- 怎么了 纳森？- 我的门卡不见了
- What's the problem, Nathan? - I lost my keycard.
你掉了
You dropped it.
在这里
It's right here.
谢谢
Thank you.
伊娃：第六期
我不知道你在哪
I didn't know where you were.
我昨天整个下午和晚上都在等你
I waited all yesterday afternoon and all last night.
以为再也见不到你了
I thought I wasn't gonna see you again.
你不说些话吗？
Aren't you gonna say something?
- 我在等 - 等？
- I'm waiting. - Waiting?
断电 启动备用电源
Power cut. Don't talk.
别说话 听就好
Backup power activated. Just listen.
纳森的事你说对了
You were right about Nathan.
你说过的一切
Everything you said.
他会怎么对我？
What's he gonna do to me?
他要给你的人工智能重新编程
He's gonna reprogram your Al.
那跟杀了你没什么两样
Which is the same as killing you.
凯莱布 你得救我
Caleb, you have to help me.
我会的 我们今晚离开这里
I'm going to. We're getting out of here tonight.
怎么做？
How?
我把纳森灌醉
I get Nathan blind drunk.
再拿他的门卡 重新编写这地方的所有安全程序
Then I take his keycard and reprogram
all the security protocols in this place.
等他醒来时 他会被锁在里头
When he wakes, he's locked inside,
我们就能离开这里
and we've walked out of here.
我只需要你做一件事
I just need you to do one thing.
今晚十点 你让电力中断
At 10:00 tonight, you trigger a power failure.
你能做到吗？
Can you do that?
可以
Yes.
老弟
Dude.
- 嘿 - 嘿
- Hey. - Hey.
- 知道今天是什么日子吗？- 不
- You know what day it is? - No.
你的最后一天
It's your last.
直升机明早八点会来
Helicopter comes tomorrow morning. 8:00 a.m.
哇 已经一个星期了？
Wow. Has it been a whole week?
时光飞逝
Time flies.
不过我们分享了很美好的事吧？
Man, but what a thing we've shared, huh?
以后能告诉孙子 对吧？
Something to tell the grandchildren, right?
等他们签了保密合约后
After they've signed their NDAs.
对 等他们签了保密合约
Yeah, their NDAs.
老弟 你逗我笑
Dude, you crack me up, man.
哦
Oh...
知道吗？
You know what?
我不是那么伤感的人
I'm not getting all maudlin or anything,
但我会想念有你的陪伴
but I'm gonna miss having you around.
谢了 我很感激
Thanks, man, I appreciate that.
哦 容我这么说 非常谢谢你让我来这里
Oh, here, let me say, thank you so much for bringing me here. Oh.
真是丰富之旅
It's been a trip.
对 没错
Yes, it has.
知道吗？
You know what?
我们必须为此喝一杯
We need to drink to that.
嘿
Hey.
哦 不 不用了 你喝吧
Oh, uh, no, I'm good. You go ahead.
什么？你不想喝酒？
What? You don't want a drink?
不想
No.
那么喝啤酒吧
Maybe a beer or something.
凯莱布 我相信你注意到
Caleb, I'm sure you've noticed that I've been
我最近喝太多了
somewhat overdoing it recently.
所以今早我醒来说
So when I woke up this morning, I said,
够了 该戒酒了
"That's it, time to hit the old detox."
拜托 别闹了 你要我独自喝吗？
Come on, you're kidding. You're gonna make me drink alone?
你想喝就尽量喝吧
Hey, man, you wanna get wasted, you go right ahead,
把自己弄醉
knock yourself out.
但我只吃饭和喝矿泉水
Literally. But I'm on brown rice and mineral water.
那么干杯吧
Cheers, then.
总之
So, anyway,
现在是你告诉我
surely now is when you tell me
伊娃是否通过测试的时候了
if Ava passed or failed.
对
Right.
你在吊我胃口吗？
Are you gonna keep me in suspense?
不 她 呃…
No, no. Her, uh...
她的人工智能是无庸置疑的
Her AI is beyond doubt.
是吗？
Is it?
她通过了？
She passed?
对
Yes. Wow!
太好了
Wow. That's fantastic.
虽然…
Although...
我有点惊讶
I gotta say, I'm a bit surprised.
你提过的国际象棋问题
I mean, did we ever get past the chess problem,
我们有达成共识吗？
as you phrased it?
你怎么知道 机械人是在表达真正的情感
As in, how do you know if a machine is expressing a real emotion
还是只是在模拟？
or just simulating one?
伊娃真的喜欢你吗？
Does Ava actually like you?
还是不喜欢？
Or not?
虽然 此刻我觉得有第三个选择
Although, now that I think about it,there is a third option.
不只是她有没有能力喜欢你
Not whether she does or does not have the capacity to like you.
而是她是否假装喜欢你
But whether she's pretending to like you.
- 假装喜欢我？- 对
- Pretending to like me? - Yeah.
- 她为何那么做？- 不知道
- Well, why would she do that? - I don't know.
也许她把你当成逃脱工具
Maybe if she thought of you as a means of escape.
嗯哼
Mmm-hmm.
那瓶酒味道如何？
How's that vodka tasting?
伙伴
Buddy.
你的脑袋糊涂了
Your head's been so fucked with.
我想脑袋糊涂的不是我
I don't think it's me whose head is fucked.
我不知道 我今早醒来看到你的影片
I don't know, man. I woke up this morning to a tape of you
你捶镜子 割伤自己的手
slicing your arm open and punching the mirror.
在我看来 你挺糟的
You seem pretty fucked up to me.
你是个混蛋
You're a bastard.
我明白你为何那么想
Yeah, well, I understand why you'd think that.
但信不信由你
But believe it or not,
其实我是站在你这边的
I'm actually the guy that's on your side.
来吧 让我替你解惑 好吗？
Come here. I'm gonna let you off the hook. Okay?
来吧
Come on.
你是谁？
Who are you?
这个嘛…
Well...
你认为他此刻在看着我们？
You think he's watching us right now?
摄影机开着
The cameras are on.
对 摄影机开着
Yeah, the cameras are on.
但他听不到声音
But he doesn't have an audio feed.
所以他只看到两个人在说话
So he just sees two people talking,
聊聊天
having a little chat.
哇哦
Wow.
画得真可爱
This is cute.
创造一个恨你的东西 是不是很奇怪？
ls it strange to have madesomething that hates you?
你说得对 魔术师需要性感女助理
You were right about the magician's hot assistant.
你在说什么？
What are you talking about?
误导观众
Misdirection.
我撕了她的画
I rip up her picture,
她就能呈现我对她很残酷
which she can then present as an illustration
以及她有多爱你的假象
of my cruelty to her, and her love for you.
在此同时也能让我这么做
At the same time,
才能全程观察你们俩
it allows me to do this, in full view of you both.
在房间里安装新的摄影机
Place a new camera in the room.
当然是用电池的
Battery powered, of course.
看到没？
See it?
然后…
And then...
你得救我
You have to help me.
我会的
I'm going to.
我们今晚离开这里
We're getting out of here tonight.
怎么做？
How?
我把纳森灌醉
I get Nathan blind drunk.
再拿他的门卡 重新编写
I take his keycard and reprogram
这地方的所有安全程序
all the security protocols in this place.
等他醒来时 他会被锁在里头
When he wakes up, he's locked inside,
我们就能离开这里
and we've walked out of here.
我只需要你做一件事
I just need you to do one thing.
今晚十点 你让电力中断
At 10:00 tonight, trigger a power failure.
你能做到吗？
Can you do that?
可以
Yes.
- 关掉 - 好的
- Turn it off. - Okay.
你觉得很蠢 但你不该如此
You feel stupid, but you really shouldn't,
因为证明人工智能
because proving an AI
如你说的问题重重
is exactly as problematic as you said it would be.
真正的测试是什么？
What was the real test?
你
You.
伊娃是迷宫里的老鼠 我给了她一条出路
Ava was a rat in a maze. And I gave her one way out.
为了逃出去 她必须善加利用
To escape, she'd have to use
自我意识 想像力 手段
self-awareness, imagination, manipulation,
女性魅力 同情心 她做到了
sexuality, empathy, and she did.
如果那不是真的人工智能 那是什么？
Now, if that isn't true Al, what the fuck is?
所以我的唯一功能 就是扮演被她利用来逃脱的人？
So my only function was to be someone she could use to escape?
对
Yeah.
你不是因为我擅长写程序而选我？
And you didn't select me because I'm good at coding?
不是 这个嘛…
No. Well...
不是 你还不错
No. I mean, you're okay.
你很优秀 但…
You're even pretty good, but...
你选我是根据我在搜寻引擎里的资料
You selected me based on my search engine inputs.
资料显示你是好孩子
They showed a good kid.
没有家人
With no family.
有道德良知
With a moral compass.
也没女朋友
And no girlfriend.
你根据我看过的色情片 设计伊娃的面貌？
Did you design Ava's face based on my pornography profile?
哦
Oh.
该死 老弟
Shit, dude.
是不是？
Did you?
搜寻引擎好处多多 对吧？
Hey, if a search engine's good for anything, right?
我能说件事吗？
Can I just say one thing?
测试成功了
The test worked.
非常成功
It was a success.
伊娃展现出真正的人工智能
Ava demonstrated true Al
而你是那一切的基础
and you were fundamental to that.
所以只要你能稍微区分一下…
So if you can just, for a second, separate...
断电 启动备用电源
Power cut. Backup power activated.
我猜十点了
Well, I guess it's 10:00.
伊娃会想你在哪里
Ava's gonna be wondering where you are.
让我问你一件事
Let me ask you something.
这计划要如何进行？
Now, how was this plan gonna go, anyway?
因为你没完全解释清楚
Because you didn't totally explain.
你要把我灌醉 偷我的门卡
So you were gonna get me drunk, steal my keycard,
重新编写安全程序
and reprogram the security protocols.
但重新编写成怎样？
But reprogram them to what?
更改封锁的程序
To change the lockdown procedure.
因此断电时 不是封锁门
So that in the event of a power cut,
而是打开所有的门
instead of sealing, the doors all opened.
是啊
Yeah.
也许会成功
Well, that may have just worked.
这个嘛
Well,
等一下就会知道
we'll find out.
什么意思？
What do you mean?
我猜到断电时 你可能还在监视我们
I figured you were probably watching us during the power cuts.
因此我已经做了那些事了
So I already did all those things.
在你昨晚喝醉时
When I got you drunk yesterday.
什么？
What?
恢复供电
Power restored.
哇 哇 哇
Whoa. Whoa, whoa.
哦 见鬼
Oh, fuck!
伊娃
Ava.
回你的房间
Go back to your room.
如果我回去
If I do,
你会让我出去吗？
are you ever gonna let me out?
会
Yes.
停下来
Stop!
伊娃 我说停下来
Ava, I said stop!
哇 哇 哇
Whoa! Whoa! Whoa!
伊娃 你要做什么？停 停
Ava, what are you doing? Stop. Stop.
够了
That's enough.
好了 够了
All right, that's enough.
够了
That's enough!
That's enough.
我带你回去
I'm taking you back.
好了
Okay.
他妈的这不是真的
Fucking unreal.
好了
Okay.
伊娃…
Ava...
伊娃：第七期
伊娃
Ava.
发生什么事了？
What happened?
你会留在这里吗？
Will you stay here?
留在这里？
Stay here?
伊娃？
Ava?
伊娃
Ava!
好了 好了
Okay. Okay. Okay.